Guide to the Rights and Wrongs Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Programs, 1993-1996; Series IV
  - Heroes of Human Rights, 1996 July 3; 411
    The program consists of segments on At the Edge of the Conflict " featuring Chief Wai-Wai of the Waiapi people, who fought for and won land rights for indigenous people in the Amazon jungle of Brazil; Guatemalan Nobel Laureate Rigoberta Menchu, an advocate for Indigenous and women's rights. *Journalist Roy Gutman and documentary filmmaker Ademir Kenovic chronicle the war in the former Yugoslavia; the memorial to Veronica Guerin, a journalist killed while covering the war in Ireland; a profile of Richard N'Sanzabagoma, a human rights activist in Rwanda; a profile of Geoffrey Canada, who defends the rights of children in Harlem, New York; and a conversation with Elie Wiesel, Nobel Peace Prize recipient.
    - Master, 1 (Box 178)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 178D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 178U)
  - Nigeria, 1996 July 10; 412
    The program consists of reports on the human rights situation in Nigeria, focusing on the elections aborted by the military regime, the role of the US government and Shell Oil, the execution of a prominent human rights activist, and the worldwide response to the situation; lobbying efforts in the US by various American corporations, non-profit organizations, Nigerian nationals, and the American public; and an excerpt from "Ken Saro-Wiwa: an African Martyr," the final interview with the Nigerian human rights activist who fought for the Ogoni people and an end to the oppressive and illegal regime ruling Nigeria.
    - Master, 1 (Box 179)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 179D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 179U)
  - War on Drugs and Human Rights, 1996 July 17; 413
    the program consists of reports on the impact of the drug war on the rights of individuals, minorities, and the judicial system; Prison Life Magazine, founded by a former drug pusher and an undercover DEA agent, advocates on behalf of prisoners convicted in the "War on Drugs"; and General Barry McCaffrey, President Clinton's drug "Czar," discussing his views on drug policy and the current state of the "War on Drugs".
    - Master, 1 (Box 180)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 180D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 180U)
  - Child Labor II, 1996 July 24; 414
    The program consists of segment on United States corporations and their use of child labor and how consumers and public opinion can change these practices; excerpts from My Life is Mine, a documentary about the life of a child worker in Pakistan's brick kiln industry; and Bob Herbert, New York Times columnist, discussing the response of American corporations to the public outcry against child labor.
    - Master, 1 (Box 181)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 181D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 181U)